Jacob Bloom

Contact Information

jacobbloom.dev mr.jacob.bloom@gmail.com github.com/mrjacobbloom

Languages

Seasoned JavaScript / TypeScript HTML5 CSS / SASS

Proficient

C / C++ Python SOL

Technical Skills

Web Design / Front-End React / JSX / TSX Web Animations SVG / Canvas Bootstrap iQuery Web Accessibility Responsive Design Node.js / Back-End Mocha / Chai MongoDB Git / GitHub / TFVC Regular Expressions Interpreters / Parsers

Other Skills

MIDI

Graphic Design Photoshop / Adobe CC Customer Service Music Production Singing / Piano Choral Arrangement Choral Direction

I'm a fun, energetic, resourceful full-stack developer with a passion for JavaScript. I have egregious levels of experience in both clientand server-side JS. I'm well-versed in a few other languages and pick up new ones quickly!

Work Experience

^{2019-now} Anark Corp. - Software Engineer - MBEWeb Team

- Product: cloud-based technical content hosting
- I spearheaded client side of Work Management suite
- · I mostly did front-end development
- · Company operated under Agile principles
- MERN+TypeScript stack, Mocha+Chai test suite

2017-2019

CU Boulder - ServiceNow Student Developer

- CU's IT used a SaaS issue tracker/ticketing system
- We provided support & custom-built solutions
- · I oversaw development of a Node+Selenium test suite
- · I developed new user onboarding course and videos

²⁰¹⁵⁻²⁰¹⁷ CU Boulder - Service Center Student Lead Analyst

- · We provided tech support to the CU Boulder campus over the phone, via email, and online
- I built tooling to improve personal & team workflows

Education

University of Colorado Boulder (2015-2019)

- BA in Computer Science
- Major GPA 3.5
- · Certificate in Design Technologies

Projects

Natural Neighbors Js

- Lead Developer / UI Design
- · Agile group project in a Software Development class
- Express.js, Travis CI, Heroku
- · Social Network for wildlife enthusiasts to post about animal sightings

Notochord Js

- Ongoing personal project
- Jazz lead-sheet editor / chord player
- · Domain-specific language for declaratively describing musical styles

Gnatural neighbors



Activities

In The Buff Men's A Cappella - Music Director

- Member 2015-2019
- 2 years as Marketing Director before taking on Music Director
- · Oversaw recording, licensing & distributing an album
- Managed preparations for 25th Anniversary concert